# SOUVIK SARKAR.

## Programmer + Writer

sounix000@gmail.com ◊ (+91) 6360229130 ◊ sounix000.github.io

#### **OVERVIEW**

Technical Writer with 8 years of experience documenting software and APIs for developers and administrators, backed by 4 years of experience as a developer. I develop technical content for optimal developer experience, using docs-as-code, modular documentation, and open-source tools.

#### **SKILLS**

Programming C/C++, Python, Bash, JavaScript
Markup AsciiDoc, Markdown, XML, HTML

DeploymentGitHub, Docker, KubernetesCloudGoogle Cloud PlatformImages/DiagramsInkscape, Mermaid.js

Code/Text Editors VS Code, Vim

Projects and Analytics JIRA, Google Sheets

## **EMPLOYMENT**

SUSE March 2023 - Present

Senior Technical Writer

- · Own the guides for performance tuning and security of SUSE Linux Enterprise.
- · Contribute to transitioning from monolithic guides to topic-based modular documentation for SUSE Linux Enterprise.
- · Collaborate with engineers, release managers, and product managers to realign SUSE Linux Enterprise documentation with the upstream OpenSUSE documentation.
- · Interface with support engineering team for reinforcing existing documentation and creating clientspecific knowledge-base articles.
- · Participate in peer reviews and mentor new technical writers in the team.
- · Technologies/Tools: SUSE Linux Enterprise, OpenSUSE Leap, Bash, Python, DocBook XML, AsciiDoc, GitHub, VS Code, SUSE style guide, JIRA, Confluence Wiki, Slack.

Red Hat November 2020 - March 2023

Senior Technical Writer

- · Lead documentation efforts for OpenShift CI/CD Pipelines, including triaging issues, creating documentation plans, and deciding content strategy.
- · Participated in peer reviews of documents for other products, and mentored new technical writers in the team.
- · Collaborated with content strategists and product managers to realign product documentation with upstream documentation.
- · Interfaced with the support engineering team to reinforce existing documentation and create clientspecific knowledge-base articles.
- · Analyzed data to improve the coverage, flow, architecture, findability, and accessibility of documentation.
- · Technologies/Tools: Fedora Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, Golang, Node.js, Bash, AsciiDoc, Markdown, Lucidchart, GitHub, VS Code, Atom, IBM style guide, JIRA, Trello, Tableau, Google Sheets, Slack.

#### **Ribbon Communications**

January 2019 - November 2020

Senior Technical Writer

- · Lead documentation efforts for SBC Core, resulting in improved customer satisfaction ratings.
- · Developed documents such as CLI reference and REST API user guide.
- · Participated in peer reviews of documents for other products, and mentored new technical writers in the team.
- · Collaborated in revamping the internal style guide to make onboarding new technical writers easier.
- · Technologies/Tools: Proprietary networking and telecom hardware, Debian Linux, C++, Bash, Open-Stack, AWS, Confluence Wiki, Snagit, Microsoft style guide, JIRA.

## FusionCharts (Infosoft Global Pvt. Ltd.)

March 2018 - January 2019

Technical Content Writer

- · Developed and reviewed sample applications, code snippets, and content for developer documentation.
- · Implemented automation scripts to improve the operational efficiency of pre-release workflows.
- · Worked with engineering and marketing teams to create and publish technical articles on third-party websites and blogs.
- · Technologies/Tools: macOS, JavaScript (Node.js, Vue.js, React.js), Markdown, Lucidchart, Google style guide, GitHub, Trello, Slack.

Tata Elxsi

June 2016 - March 2018

Consultant Technical Writer

Contractor for Ribbon Communications

- · Created and maintained Quick-start tutorials, API guides, User guides, and Release Notes.
- · Technologies/Tools: Proprietary networking and telecom hardware, Debian Linux, Confluence Wiki, Snagit, Microsoft style guide, JIRA.

#### Agaze Technologies

September 2015 - May 2016

Software Engineer

- $\cdot$  Developed internal and client-facing applications, focusing on the back-end implementation.
- Technologies/Tools: Ubuntu Linux, Python (Django, Flask), PostgreSQL, JavaScript (Node.js, React.js), Google Cloud Platform (App Engine).

### Freelance/Self-employed

July 2012 - August 2015

Web Developer

- · Developed websites, administered systems, and wrote technical content for blogs as a ghostwriter.
- · Technologies/Tools: Ubuntu Linux, Python (Flask), MySQL, JavaScript.

#### RECOGNITIONS

**Red Hat** - Several peer-to-peer awards from team members (including engineering) for collaboration and commitment to excellence.

Ribbon Communications - Motivate Award (2019-2020) for extraordinary performance.

Tata Elxsi - Customer Appreciation Award (2016-2017) based on client recommendation.

### **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor of Technology

2014